(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
コンアキ！1期生のアキ・ローゼンタールです！
Kon-Aki! I'm Aki Rosenthal from the first generation!
Welcome to Aki Rose World!
たった一つの たった一つの
The one and only, the one and only,
たった一人 たった一人の
私はここ
I am here.
瓦礫の胸 息もできない
My heart is in ruins, I can't even breathe.
降り出す雨 眠るように
Like the rain that starts to fall, as if sleeping.
暗い
Dark.
この世界を 生き抜くのならば
If I am to survive in this world,
どんな花を 飾ればいいの
What kind of flowers should I display?
信じたいくせに
Even though I want to believe,
信じられずに
I still can't.
無力で無意味な自分が
My powerless and meaningless self,
それでも心で泣いたんだ
was still crying in my heart.
こっちへおいでと 声が聞こえる
I hear a voice saying, "Come over here."
無限で無謀な明日が
An infinite and reckless tomorrow,
それでもどこかで待つから
is still waiting for me somewhere.
たった一つと
With only one
たった一人 たった一人と
With only one person, just one person
私 まごころ
I, sincerity
たぶん少しか許したくない
Maybe just a little, I don't want to forgive
半分しか分かり合えない
We can only understand each other halfway
この世界を戦い抜くなら
If I'm going to fight through this world
どんな歌を歌えばいいの
What kind of song should I sing?
見つけたいなら
If you want to find it
見つけだすまで
Until you find it
不実で不毛な自由も
Even an unfaithful and fruitless freedom
それでも欲しいと叫んだ
I still cried out that I wanted it
知ってるくせに知らぬフリをして
Even though you know, you pretend not to
無色で無傷な光を
A colorless and painless light
それでももう一度探した
I searched for it once more regardless
たった一つ たった一つの
Just one, just one
たった一人 たった一人の
Just one person, just one person
私 まごころ
I, sincerity
君だけの場所が
A place just for you
必ずある
Definitely exists
美しいこの星は全てを
This beautiful planet hides everything
隠してるけど
But...
無力で無意味な自分が
My powerless and meaningless self
それでも心で泣いたんだ
Still cried in my heart
こっちへおいでと声が聞こえる
I hear a voice saying "Come over here"
無限で無謀な明日が
An infinite and reckless tomorrow
それでもどこかで待つから
Because it's waiting for me somewhere
たった一つ たった一つの
Just one, just one
たった一人 たった一人の
Just one person, just one person
私 まごころ
I, sincerity
アローナ！ちゃんと見えてる？聞こえてる？
Alona! Can you see me? Can you hear me?
ということでホロライブ1期生の
And so, I'm the 1st gen Hololive
癒やし系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼです！
healing half-elf, AkiRose!
今日は4周年記念ライブ、
Today, I'm presenting my 4th Anniversary LIVE,
ROSE of the LAMPをお送りしております！
"ROSE of the LAMP"!
歌だけのライブは初めてで緊張するけど、
This is my first all-singing live, so I'm nervous, but...
心を込めてアキロゼワールドを楽しんでもらえるように頑張ります！
I'll do my best so you can enjoy the AkiRose world with all my heart!
一緒にお祝いしてください！
Please celebrate with me!
たくさんのゲストも来るので、お楽しみに！
Many guests will be coming, so look forward to it!
それでは、ROSE of the LAMP、お楽しみください！
Well then, please enjoy "ROSE of the LAMP"!
幸せになれる隠しコマンドがあるらしい
There seems to be a hidden command that makes you happy
作詞：鳥居羊　作曲：うたたP
Lyrics: Hitsuji Torii / Composition: Utata-P
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下
Up, Up, Down, Down
ちょっと上に溜めてください
Please charge it upwards for a bit
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 回転　回転
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Spin, Spin
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 回転　反転　回転
Up, Up, Down, Down, Spin, Flip, Spin
無茶振りじゃないか 不可能可能に
Isn't that an unreasonable request? Making the impossible possible
とにかくやれって 命令ばかり
Just orders telling me to do it anyway
なせばなるって 精神論
The "where there's a will, there's a way" spiritualism
マイナスばかり 溜まって 爆発寸前
Only negatives are piling up, I'm on the verge of exploding
みんな！ここまでの隠しコマンドを
Everyone! If you complete the hidden commands
正確にコンプリートするか、
accurately up to this point,
チャンネル登録をすると、
or subscribe to the channel,
私たちがもっとセクシーな姿に...！
we'll turn into an even sexier form...!
なりません。
That won't happen.
右下 B A X Y L R 上 上 下 A Y L R A
Right, Down, B, A, X, Y, L, R, Up, Up, Down, A, Y, L, R, A
右 下 上 右 A X Y R
Right, Down, Up, Right, A, X, Y, R
上 上 下 下 左
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left
回転、一回転
Spin, one full spin
右下 B A X Y L R 上 上 下 A Y L R A
Right, Down, B, A, X, Y, L, R, Up, Up, Down, A, Y, L, R, A
右 下 上 右 A X Y R
Right, Down, Up, Right, A, X, Y, R
上 上 下 下
Up, Up, Down, Down
ちょっと、間違えないでください。
Hold on, please don't make mistakes.
むちゃぶりじゃないか 学校 会社
Isn't this a ridiculous request? School, work,
頭ごなしの 命令ばかり
Only dictatorial orders
なせばなるって 精神論
That "you can do it if you try" mentality
マイナスばかり 黙って 馬鹿馬鹿馬鹿
Only negatives, shut up, stupid stupid stupid
ここまでの隠しコマンドを正確にコメントするか、
If you comment all the secret commands correctly,
チャンネル登録をすると、もっとセクシーな姿に…
or subscribe to the channel, to a more sexy appearance...
なりません。
That won't happen.
まだまだ大丈夫！行けますよね？
Still okay! You can do it, right?
難易度高すぎるかもしれませんけど、あなたなら出来るでしょう？
The difficulty might be too high, but you can do it, right?
居残り 補習 出張 残業
After school, supplementary lessons, business trip, overtime
とにかくやってもらわないと… とても困ります。
Anyway, you have to do it... or I'll be in trouble.
居残り 補習 出張 残業
After school, supplementary lessons, business trip, overtime
宿題 課題 テスト 卒論
Homework, assignment, test, graduation thesis
依頼 任務 命令 締切
Request, mission, order, deadline
納期 期日 提出 明日
Delivery, due date, submission, tomorrow
部活 試合 練習 勝利
Club, match, practice, victory
業者 商談 接待 成立
Client, business talk, entertainment, settlement
進学 就職 転職 面接
Higher education, employment, job change, interview
回転 一回転
Spin, one full spin
後輩 先輩 先生 上司
Junior, senior, teacher, boss
右 下 A Y 上 L 右
Right, Down, A, Y, Up, L, Right
友人 同僚 彼 彼女
Friend, colleague, boyfriend, girlfriend
上 上 下 下 左 右 Y L
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Y, L
疲労 心労 問答無用
Fatigue, mental fatigue, no questions asked
セレクト スタート A B Y L
Select, Start, A, B, Y, L
R X 右 左
R, X, Right, Left
上下同時押し
Press up and down at the same time
むちゃぶりじゃないか 不可能 可能
Isn't this a ridiculous request? Impossible, possible
とにかくやれって 命令ばかり
Just do it, only orders
なせばなるって 精神論
That "you can do it if you try" mentality
マイナスばかり 黙って 馬鹿馬鹿馬鹿
Only negatives, shut up, stupid stupid stupid
むちゃぶりじゃないか 学校 会社
Isn't this a ridiculous request? School, work,
頭ごなしの 命令ばかり
Only dictatorial orders
なせばなるって 精神論
That "you can do it if you try" mentality
マイナスばかり 黙って 馬鹿馬鹿馬鹿
Only negatives, shut up, stupid stupid stupid
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
右 下 上 右 右 下 右 右
Right, Down, Up, Right, Right, Down, Right, Right
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右
Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right
リセット
Reset
あわれみをください 落ちた小鳥に
Please have pity on the fallen bird
そっと触れるような 悲しみをください
Please give me a sadness as gentle as a soft touch
涙ぐんで 見下ろして
With teary eyes, look down at me
可哀想だと口に出して
And say "how pitiful" out loud
靴の先で 転がしても構わないわ
I don't mind even if you roll me with the tip of your shoe
汚れててもいいからと 泥だらけの手を取って
Saying it's okay even if it's dirty, and taking my mud-covered hand
ねえ 輪になって踊りましょう
Hey, let's dance in a circle
目障りな有象無象は全て
All the eyesore masses,
食べてしまいましょう
Let's eat them all up
スパイスは 耐え難いくらいがいいわ
The spice, it's better if it's almost unbearable
怯えた小鳥は さよならなんて言えなくて
The frightened bird couldn't even say goodbye
愛を請う仕草で 黙り込んで
With a gesture of begging for love, falling silent
慎ましく つもりでいた
I intended to be modest
散々傷ついて 優しい世界に
Deeply wounded, into a gentle world
誰だって行きたいわ
Anyone would want to go
ひとつに溶けてしまいましょう
Let's melt together into one
憎しみも愛情も むしゃむしゃと頬張ってしまいましょう
Let's gobble up both hatred and affection
混沌の甘い甘い壺の中で
Inside the sweet, sweet jar of chaos
曖昧に笑うから
Because you smile so vaguely,
逢いたいと思わないのよ
I don't think I want to see you
I know you're here to stay with me
愛されていたいだけ
I just want to be loved
雷鳴の咲くところ
Where the thunder blooms
燦々だとヘブンリー
It's dazzling and heavenly
愛だけ残ればいい
I only want love to remain
しんしんと降り積もる
Falling silently and piling up
寂しさだけが降り積もる
Only the loneliness piles up
願望も懐古も
Desires and reminiscence
ただ埋め尽くす
Are simply buried away
いつか結んだ
The promise we once made
遠い春の日の
On that distant spring day
指切りさえも
Even that pinky promise
消えてしまうの
Is starting to fade away
やがて煌めく夢の中
Soon, within a glittering dream
朽ちてゆく
I'll decay
光はあなたに
Because the light is sure
届くはずだから
To reach you
眩しくて
It's so bright
涙が止まらない
I can't stop my tears
ねえどうかそばにいて
Hey, please stay by my side
泥だらけの手を取って
Take my mud-covered hand
離さないで
And don't let go
どうかずっとそばにいて
Please stay by my side forever
離さないで
Don't let go
暗くなるな そばにいて
Don't let it get dark, stay with me
離さないで
Don't let go
見えないわ ただずっと
I can't see, just stay
そばにいて
By my side forever
離さないで
Don't let go
ただずっと
Just forever...
愛してる
I love you
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There's no flower in this world more beautiful than an artificial one
なぜならすべては嘘でできている
Because everything is made of lies
アンチパシーは
Antipathy is...
フォニイ 作詞・作曲 ツミキ
Phony / Lyrics & Composition: Tsumiki
ラルラリラ
La lu la li la
タラルラリタ
Ta la lu la li ta
イェイイェイイェイイェイイェイ
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair beats against my umbrella
湿らす前髪と心の裏面
Dampening my bangs and the back of my heart
煩わしいわ
It's so annoying
いつしか言の葉はとうに枯れきって
Before I knew it, words had already withered away
言の身が多種に熟れている
And the fruit of words is ripening in many forms
鏡に映り嘘描いて
Painting lies reflected in the mirror
自らを見失ったメイク
Makeup that has lost sight of itself
パッパッパラッパッパッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa-pa
メゾンメゾン
Maison, maison
数えて遊びましょう
Let's count them up and play
タッタラタッタラタッタッタ
Ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta
何ぜ何ぜ
Why, oh why
ここで踊ってるのでしょう
Am I dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand the simplest things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の手法にほだされて
Even that is swayed by the night's methods
愛のように
Like love
さよならも言えないまま泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony
嘘に絡まっている
Tangled up in lies
あたしはフォニイ
I am a phony
アンチパシーは
Antipathy is...
いつしかサヨナラが嫌になって
At some point, I grew tired of goodbyes
色濃い眼差しを解いている
Unraveling that deeply-colored gaze
鏡に映るあたしを描いて
Drawing the "me" reflected in the mirror
誰もが身間違ったフェイク
A fake that everyone mistook
どうして愛なんてものに群がり
Why do they swarm over something like love
それを欲して生きるのだ
And live while desiring it?
今日も泳いでる夜の電車が
Today, too, the night train swims by
通り去って行く
Passing me on its way
踊り明かせよパッパッパラッパッパッパ
Dance the night away, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa
メゾンメゾン
Maison, maison
騙して歌いましょう
Let's sing while deceiving
タッタラタッタラタッタッタ
Ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta
何ぜ何ぜ
Why, oh why
ここが痛むのでしょう
Does it hurt here?
燦々な日々は変わらないわ
These brilliant days don't change
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair doesn't stop
さよならも言えないまま泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony
嘘に絡まっている
Tangled up in lies
ただ
Just...
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand the simplest things
あたしって...
What am I...
いつもだけ
Only as always,
それすら夜の手に解されて
Even that is unraveled by the hands of the night
愛の罠に
Into the trap of love.
さよなら　またねとつぶやいた
Whispering "Goodbye, see you again",
フォニイ　フォニイ　フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony.
嘘に絡まってる
Entangled in lies,
あたしはフォニイ
I am phony.
造花だけが知ってる　秘密のフォニイ
Only artificial flowers know the secret phony.
色彩のブルース / 作詞：中納良恵 / 作曲：中納良恵/森雅樹
Shikisai no Blues / Lyrics: Yoshie Nakano / Composition: Yoshie Nakano, Masaki Mori
昨日の夢　オレンジ色の影に
Yesterday's dream, in the orange-colored shadows,
今日の夢　沈黙の気配しめす
Today's dream shows a hint of silence.
アルコールの川をゆっくり渡る
Slowly crossing the river of alcohol,
長靴のリズム　心で酔いましょう
Let's get drunk with our hearts to the rhythm of boots.
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
The melody flowing from leaden fingers,
激しく染める　光の渦
A vortex of light, dyeing it all intensely,
灯りの色が奏でるブルース
The blues played by the colors of light,
やさしく泣いてる吐息に甘えさせて
Let me indulge in the gently crying sighs.
期待のカップ　裏通りの風景が
A cup of anticipation, back alley scenery,
ひしめき合う　しゃがれた声の香水
Crowding together, the perfume of raspy voices.
モノクロームの中に封じ込めた姿を
The figure sealed within monochrome,
遠い約束　リズムで交わしましょう
Let's exchange distant promises with the rhythm.
吐き出す言葉に熱いメロディー
A hot melody in the words spat out,
せつなく蘇るデジャブの香り
The painfully recurring scent of déjà vu,
心を溶かす色彩のブルース
The Shikisai no Blues that melts the heart,
甘くささやいた吐息が眠るまで
Until the sweetly whispered sighs fall asleep.
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
The melody flowing from leaden fingers,
激しく染める　光の渦
A vortex of light, dyeing it all intensely,
灯りの色が奏でるブルース
The blues played by the colors of light,
やさしく泣いてる吐息に甘えさせて
Let me indulge in the gently crying sighs.
吐き出す言葉に熱いメロディー
A hot melody in the words spat out,
せつなく蘇るデジャブの香り
The painfully recurring scent of déjà vu,
心を溶かす色彩のブルース
The Shikisai no Blues that melts the heart,
ささやいた吐息が
Whispered breaths
眠るまで
Until I fall asleep
ストレイト ドキドキする
Straight, making my heart race
視線はまるでレーザービーム
Your gaze is just like a laser beam
心をシュワリと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam
レーザービーム
作詞・作曲：中田ヤスタカ
Laser Beam
Lyrics & Composition: Yasutaka Nakata
実るかな いつか
Will it bear fruit someday?
水を弾いて
Repelling the water
キラキラしてる
Sparkling so bright
光に似てる
Resembling the light
グラウンドに立つ
Standing on the field
君の姿が
The sight of you
眩しくて少し照れちゃうけど
Is so dazzling it makes me a bit shy
ストレイト まっすぐだね
Straight, you're so direct
願いはきっとレーザービーム
My wish is surely a laser beam
心をシュワリと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam
二人を繋ぐ
The secret light
秘密の光
That connects us two
あの日見つけた
That secret light
秘密の光
We found that day
恋の瞬間
In the moment of love
音は集まって
Sounds gather together
時間はスローに
Time moves slowly
恋の光線
A beam of love
ストレイト ドキドキする
Straight, making my heart race
視線はまるでレーザービーム
Your gaze is just like a laser beam
心をシュワリと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam
ストレイト まっすぐだね
Straight, you're so direct
恋愛はきっとレーザービーム
Love is surely a laser beam
心をシュワリと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam
私とテイクステップ イェイ
Take a step with me, yeah
狂い咲くバラ色の夜
A rose-colored night in full bloom
夢を乗せて踊りましょう
Let's dance with our dreams
ROSE of the LAMP
作詞：志村真白(FirstCall) 作曲：EFFY(FirstCall)
Lyrics: Mashiro Shimura, Composition: EFFY
だってもっと触れたい
Because I want to touch you more,
知りたい
I want to know you,
隠した想い
these hidden feelings.
ときどきラブロマンティック
Sometimes it's love-romantic.
ときには甘く触れた 果実のように
Sometimes touching sweetly, like fruit,
君にそっと囁くの
I'll whisper softly to you.
情熱の誘うままに ねえ
Just as passion leads me, hey,
本当の素顔見せて
show me your true face.
Wanna be Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love 私のすべてを
Wanna be, Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love, all of me.
だって Crazy Crazy Love, Crazy Crazy Love 本気見せてあげる
Because it's Crazy Crazy Love, Crazy Crazy Love, I'll show you I'm serious.
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 君と出会えた奇跡に
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, to the miracle of meeting you,
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 愛を込めて踊りましょう
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, let's dance with all our love.
歌って 笑って 悩んで 迷える日々も なんて素敵なドラマティック
Singing, laughing, worrying, even those days of being lost—how wonderful and dramatic.
そうやって探って 感じて 重ね合わせて
Searching, feeling, and layering them together like that,
君にちょっと近づくの
I'll get a little closer to you.
鼓動が叫ぶくらい ほら
So much that my heart screams, look,
炎より強く光って
shining brighter than a flame.
さぁよ Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love 溶かしてあげるわ
Come on, Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love, I'll melt you away.
きっと Funny Funny Love, Funny Funny Love もう止められないの
Surely it's Funny Funny Love, Funny Funny Love, it can't be stopped anymore.
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ こんな素晴らしい世界に
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, in this wonderful world,
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 君のために踊りましょう
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, let's dance for you.
まぁ Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love 私のすべてを
More Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love, all of me.
ベイビー君だけに 君だけに 全部届けたいよ
Baby, to you alone, to you alone, I want to deliver everything.
まぁ Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love 私のすべてを
More Give me Give me Love, Give me Give me Love, all of me.
だって Crazy Crazy Love, Crazy Crazy Love 本気見せてあげる
Because it's Crazy Crazy Love, Crazy Crazy Love, I'll show you I'm serious.
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 君と出会えた奇跡に
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, to the miracle of meeting you,
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 愛を込めて踊りましょう
Abracadabra, Abracadabra, let's dance with all our love.
はい！ということでアキロゼの新曲がきたぞー！
Yes! So, AkiRose's new song is here!
6月2日0時、なので今日の夜中に発売開始、配信開始なので
It'll be released at midnight on June 2nd, which is tonight, so it'll be available for streaming and purchase,
ぜひぜひ買ってください！
so please definitely check it out!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よし、じゃあまだまだ盛り上がっていくぞ！
Alright, let's keep the excitement going!
続いてはこの曲だ！
Next up is this song!
MOON PRIDE あなたの力になりたい
MOON PRIDE, I want to be your strength.
涙は頬を伝い
Tears stream down the cheeks,
瞳は赤く燃える
eyes burn red.
稲妻のように激しく
Violent like lightning,
誰かが愛を叫ぶ
someone screams of love.
たとえどんな
No matter how deep...
暗闇 ひとりじゃないよね
...the darkness, you're not alone, right?
照らす Moonlight
The moonlight that shines upon us.
ああ 女の子にも
Ah, girls too have...
譲れぬ矜持がある
...a pride they cannot yield.
それは王子様に運命投げず
It's the will to fight for themselves,
自ら戦う意志
not leaving their fate to a prince.
Shiny Make-up 輝くよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll shine
星空を集めて
gathering the starry sky
ただ守られるだけの
I'm not just a fragile being
かよわい存在じゃないわ
waiting to be protected
悲しみの波に揺られ
Swayed by waves of sadness
怒りの火に焼かれても
even if burned by the fires of anger
稲妻のように眩く
Dazzling like a lightning bolt
永遠の愛を誓う
I swear my eternal love
たとえ今が 独りじゃない
Even if for now, we're not alone
私たち
the four of us
繋ぐムーンライト
joined by the moonlight
ああ 女の子には
Ah, every girl possesses
無敵の武器がある
an invincible weapon
それは弱さに寄り添う眼差しと
It's a gaze that stays close to weakness
全て受け入れる強さ
and the strength to accept everything
Shiny Make-up 煌めくよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll sparkle
星空に抱かれて
held by the starry sky
時を越えた絆が
Bonds that transcend time
私に勇気をくれる
give me courage
恋しくて 切なくて
So dear, so painful
泣きたくなるよ
it makes me want to cry
会いたくて 寂しくて
I want to see you, I'm so lonely
駆け出しそうなハート
my heart feels like it's racing off
この広い宇宙で
In this vast universe
何度生まれ変わっても
no matter how many times I'm reborn
貴方に恋をする
I'll fall in love with you
Shiny Make-up 羽ばたくよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll take flight
星空の彼方へ
to the far side of the starry sky
罪が回る世界でも
Even in a world where sins revolve
未来を信じられる だから
I can believe in the future, that's why
Shiny Make-up 戦うよ
Shiny Make-up, I'll fight
星空を纏って
clad in the starry sky
新しい伝説が
A new legend
今ここから始まる
begins right here, right now
La La Pretty Guardian
Sailor Moon
せーの！
One, two!
4周年おめでとうー！
Happy 4th Anniversary!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
じゃあせっかくだし、4周年のお祝いなんだから他の1期生も呼んじゃおうか！
Well, since it's my 4th anniversary celebration, should I invite the other 1st generation members too?
いいねー！
Sounds good!
じゃあ頑張ってねー！
Good luck then!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よし、じゃあメルちゃん行きますか！
Alright, then, Mel-chan, shall we go?
うん！
Yeah!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
Plasmagic Seasons!
輝くよ空 四季巡って
The sky shines as the seasons cycle
春風で君を乗せて
Carrying you on the spring breeze
夏色が迎えるよ
summer colors welcome us
煌めくときが背中を押したら
When the sparkling time pushes your back
舞い舞う吹雪煌めき
Dancing snowstorms sparkle
移りゆくハート
with a changing heart
何も分からず一歩進んで
Taking a step forward without knowing anything
やっとここまで辿り着けたね
we've finally made it this far
待っている ずっと
Waiting forever
素敵なステージ
for a wonderful stage
一番に
As the very first
絶対に見せてあげるよ
I'll definitely show it to you
Oh, Smile Smile, Catch a Future!
無邪気に回る季節が
The innocently spinning seasons
世界を駆け巡って
run all around the world
夢のような日々へと
Into days that feel like a dream
惹かれれば Bright Light, Catch a Future!
if attracted, Bright Light, Catch a Future!
僕らが一等星
We are the first-magnitude stars
そうさ照らし続けよう
yes, let's keep on shining
スポットライトはついたばかり
The spotlight has only just come on
朝な夕な 微笑むイルミネーション
Morning and evening, smiling illumination
心パッ！ 色とりどり
Heart goes pop! Multi-colored
弾け舞う 跳ね回る
bursting and dancing, bouncing around
幸せいっぱい 注ぐ
Pouring out plenty of happiness
...プラス
...plus
鳴らして　キラっとサバイバルよ
Sound it out, it's a sparkling survival.
真っ白な気持ち
Pure white feelings.
12時の鐘なんか　忘れちゃって
Just forget about the 12 o'clock bell.
ずっと解けない魔法を　かけよう
Let's cast a spell that never breaks.
トキメキ増して
Increasing the excitement.
そっと胸踊る時間は
The time when my heart dances quietly...
送るから
...because I'll send it to you.
絶対ついておいでよ (Oh!)
Definitely follow me (Oh!)
スパッ　スパッ　スパークル！フューチャー　今追いかけるいつつ星
Sparkle! Future, now chasing the five stars.
世界を　巻き込んで　賑やかに遊ぼう
Let's involve the world and play lively.
ずっとフラッシュ！フラッシュ！まわりまわるでしょう
Forever flash! Flash! It'll keep going round and round.
カーテンコールの　ずっとずっと先まで
To far beyond the curtain call.
イェーイ！盛り上がってっかーい！
Yeah! Are you guys having fun?
夏色まつりは清楚だよなー！
Natsuiro Matsuri is pure and innocent, right?
はあちゃまっちゃまー！
Haachama-chama!
バッツバツ！
Batsu batsu!
ジャジャーン！アロハ！みんなありまーす！
Ta-da! Aloha! Thank you everyone!
楽しむ気持ち　持って来たら
If you bring your feelings of enjoyment...
きっと誰でも主役になれるよ
...surely anyone can become the star.
派手な衣装も笑顔もさらけ出して
Reveal your flashy outfits and smiles.
もっとステップ！もっとジャンプ！
More steps! More jumps!
またどない　この世界を
This world that has no equal...
一緒に遊び尽くそう (Oh!)
...let's play through it together (Oh!)
響けクラップ！クラップ！レッツシング！フューチャー　このメロディが終わっても
Resonate clap! clap! Let's sing! Future, even if this melody ends.
決して今日だけの思い出にはしないよ
I'll never let it be just a memory of today.
行こうスマイル！スマイル！キャッチ！フューチャー
Let's go smile! smile! Catch! Future.
無邪気にまわる季節が　世界を駆け巡って　夢のような日々へと
The innocently rotating seasons run through the world, towards dream-like days.
光れブライト！ブライト！ライト！フューチャー　僕らが灯す光は
Shine bright! bright! light! future, the light we ignite...
そうさ　照らし続けよう
...that's right, let's keep illuminating.
スポットライトは　終わらない
The spotlight will not end.
5年目も　がんば　ろーぜー！
In our 5th year too, let's do our best!
ということで、1期生オリジナル曲「Plasmagic Seasons!」をお送りしましたー！
And with that, we presented the 1st generation original song "Plasmagic Seasons!"
そして、1期生の周年記念ウィークが、開幕だー！
And the 1st generation anniversary week has begun!
みんなの記念配信やお知らせがあれば、ここでどんとお願いします！じゃあ、メルちゃんから！
If everyone has anniversary streams or announcements, please share them here! Let's start with Mel-chan!
はい、魔界の天才ヴァンパイア夜空メルです！あきちゃん今日誘ってくれてありがとう！
Yes, I'm the genius vampire of the underworld, Yozora Mel! Aki-chan, thank you for inviting me today!
またね1期生ののみんなでこの曲が歌えて、メルはとっても嬉しかったです！
Mel was so happy to be able to sing this song with everyone from the 1st generation again!
えー、そしてメルも5月13日に活動4周年を迎えておりました！
And I also celebrated my 4th anniversary on May 13th!
まだ3D配信はできていないんですが、予定はあるので、みんなお楽しみに！ありがとう！
I haven't been able to do a 3D stream yet, but I have plans, so look forward to it, everyone! Thank you!
ありがとう！次ははあとちゃん！
Thank you! Next is Haato-chan!
はーい！6月2日21時から記念配信するから、見に来てねー！
Yes! I'll be doing an anniversary stream on June 2nd from 21:00, so come watch it!
そして今日は、あきちゃんおめでとう！
And for today, congratulations, Aki-chan!
おおー、ありがとう！次はフブキちゃん！
Oh, thank you! Next is Fubuki-chan!
はい！6月3日からなんと白上も記念配信があります！よろしくお願いいたしますよーい！
Yes! From June 3rd, believe it or not, Shirakami will also have an anniversary stream! Please look forward to it!
ありがとう！そしてまつりちゃん！
Thank you! And Matsuri-chan!
はーい！えーっと、6月4日に記念配信を予定しております！よろしくお願いします！はい、ありがとう！
Yes! Well, I'm planning an anniversary stream on June 4th! Please look forward to it! Yes, thank you!
ありがとう！はい、ということで、いっぱいいっぱい盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。みんな、ありがとね！
Thank you! Yes, so I'll be happy if you all cheer us on a lot. Thank everyone!
バイバーイ！あきちゃん、またね！
Bye-bye! Aki-chan, see you later!
次はムキロゼ3Dだなー、ハハハハ！
Next is Mukiroze 3D, hahaha!
あ、まつりちゃんはお残り、お残りだよ。サマーローズで歌おうと思って。
Ah, Matsuri-chan, you stay here. I want us to sing as Summer Rose.
おーい！サマーローズOK！最後までいきましょう！
Oh! Summer Rose is OK! Let's go until the end!
ドキドキするけど楽しみ。可愛く歌うよ！じゃあ準備しましょう！
I'm nervous but excited. I'll sing cutely! Well then, let's get ready!
「またね」と　笑ってみせてくれた
You smiled and said "See you later."
同じように　笑い返していたのに
Even though I was smiling back at you in the same way...
気づけば　少し滲んでいた
...before I knew it, it was a little blurred.
あなたの姿
Your figure.
あれから　いくつ夜を越えた
Since then, how many nights have passed?
窓越しの　白い画面に映った
Reflected on the white screen through the window...
あなたと...
...with you...
今もずっと
Even now, forever
ずっと見つめたまま
forever staring at you.
降りしきる雪が積もるように
Like the falling snow piling up,
この街でただあなたを想う
I'm just thinking of you in this town.
離れていても同じ空が
Even though we're apart, the same sky,
どうか見えてますように
I hope you're looking at it.
生まれて届いた優しい声が響く耳元に
A gentle voice that was born and reached me resonates in my ears.
あなたが残した道しるべ
The signpost you left behind.
世界が切り離された夜
The night the world was torn apart,
また目をつむる
I close my eyes again.
くだらないことで笑った幸せを感じてたきっと
Laughing at silly things, I'm sure I felt happy.
特別じゃない日々をもっと二人でただ過ごしたくて
I wanted to spend more ordinary days just with you.
季節が何度変わろうと隣にいたいよね
No matter how many seasons change, I want to be by your side.
それ以上何もいらないから
I don't need anything more.
降りしきる雪が積もるように
Like the falling snow piling up,
遠い街でただあなたを想う
I'm just thinking of you in a distant town.
触れ合うことができなくても
Even if we can't touch each other,
変わることなく あぁ
nothing will change, ah...
何度だってそう振り返れば
No matter how many times I look back,
あの日のあなたの言葉が 声が 会いたくなるんだよ
your words and voice from that day make me want to see you.
何度だってそう信じ合えれば
No matter how many times, if we believe in each other,
いつでも二人繋がっていられる あぁ
we can always stay connected, ah...
雪明かり照らすこの街にも
Even in this town lit by snow,
いつかは優しい春が芽吹く
a gentle spring will bud one day.
ここでまた会えたその時は
So that when we meet here again,
涙こぼさないように
I won't shed any tears.
冬の終わりを告げる淡雪
Light snow announcing the end of winter,
そのひとときに願いをのせる
I place my wish on that moment.
どんな季節も景色も
In any season or scenery,
あなたと共に同じ場所で感じてたい
I want to feel it in the same place as you.
街に柔らかな風が吹いて
A soft breeze blows through the town,
鮮やかな花が咲くその日を
and colorful flowers bloom on that day.
待ち続ける二人にも あぁ
For the two of us who keep waiting, ah,
春が訪れますように
I hope spring comes.
笑顔でまた会えますように
I hope we can meet again with a smile.
歌よ
Song
作詞：中村佳穂
作曲：Ludvig Forssell
Lyrics: Kaho Nakamura
Composition: Ludvig Forssell
（アカペラ）
(A cappella vocalizing)
（ラ、ラ、ラ...）
(La, la, la...)
歌よ
Oh song,
導いて
Lead the way.
こんな小さなメロディが
Such a tiny melody...
貫いていく世界が
Pierces through the world...
見たいの
I want to see it.
毎朝起きて探してる
Waking up every morning, I search for it.
あなたのいない未来は想像したくない
I don't want to imagine a future without you.
嫌なの
I hate the thought.
でももういない世界がわからない
But I no longer understand a world where you're gone.
私以外うまく言ってるみたい
Everyone but me seems to be getting along fine.
それでも明日は来る
Even so, tomorrow will come.
どうでしょう
I wonder how it will be.
歌よ導いて！
Oh song, lead the way!
嫌になる　みんな幸せなの
It's frustrating, how everyone is so happy.
愛している人がいるのこうして
To have someone to love like this...
一人でいると不安になる
When I'm alone, I feel so uneasy.
歌よ導いて
Oh song, lead the way.
どんなことが起きてもいい
No matter what happens, I don't care.
歌よ
Oh song,
そばにいて
Stay by my side.
愛よ
Oh love,
近づいて
Come closer.
心のそばに
作詞：細田守／中村佳穂／岩崎太整
作曲：岩崎太整
Lend Me Your Voice
Lyrics: Mamoru Hosoda / Kaho Nakamura / Taisei Iwasaki
Composition: Taisei Iwasaki
一人にしてほしいと
"I want to be left alone,"
あなたは突き放すけれど
You say, pushing me away.
本当は胸の中にあるものを
But the things deep inside your heart...
覗かれたくないのでしょう
You don't want anyone to see them, do you?
怒り恐れ悲しみ
Anger, fear, sadness...
抱え切れる夜でも口にできない
Even on nights when it's too much to bear, you can't speak a word.
聞かせて
Let me hear it.
隠そうとするあなたの声を
That voice you try so hard to hide.
見せて
Show me.
隠れてしまうあなたの心を
That heart of yours that keeps hiding away.
一人で生きて行けると
"I can live on my own,"
あなたは言い放つ
You declare so firmly.
けれど 本当は何度も
But, in truth, time after time
何度も
Time after time,
自分に言い聞かせた
I've told myself
夜が明けたのでしょう
The night has probably dawned
けどね...
But you know...
あなた
You...
あなたは
You are...
どんなあなたでも
No matter what you're like,
見たいと
I want to see you
いつも考えてしまう
I find myself always thinking that
聞かせて
Let me hear it
隠そうとする
Even that face
あなたの顔も
you try to hide
見せて
Show it to me
隠れてしまう
Your heart,
あなたの心
which ends up hidden away
聞かせて
Let me hear it
どんなことだっていいさ
Anything is fine,
ここまで聞くから
because I'll listen to everything
開いて
Open up
そばに
I want to go
行きたい
by the side
あなたの
of your...
心...
...heart.
君の銀の庭
Your Silver Garden
そっと開いたドアの向こうに
Beyond the door softly opened
壊れそうな世界はある
A fragile-looking world exists
朝が来るのか
Whether morning comes
夜になるのか
or night falls
迷いながら
While wavering,
光は綻びて
the light begins to split
声が呼ぶまでは
Until a voice calls out
もう少し遊ぼう
Let's play a little longer
花のように
Like a flower
まわる時を
the turning time
繰り返し
repeating over and over
夢はこの部屋の中で
Dreams were inside this room
優しい歌をずっと
Singing a gentle song forever
君に歌っていた
I was singing it to you
何が本当のことなの
What is the truth?
一番強く信じられる
The world I can believe in most strongly
世界を追いかけて
Chasing after it
君の銀の庭へ
To your silver garden
道に迷ったあの子が今日も
That child who lost their way is today, too,
一番早く帰り着いた
the first one to make it home
正しさよりも明るい場所を
Finding a place brighter than righteousness,
見つけながら走ればいいんだね
it's okay to just run while searching
幼い眠りを
An innocent slumber
守りたい番人
A guardian who wants to protect
大人になる門は高く
The gate to becoming an adult is high
閉ざされて
And tightly shut
...離れて
...separated
君は気付いていたかな？
Did you notice?
本当のことなんて
That the truth...
いつも過去にしかない
...is only ever in the past?
未来や希望はすべて
Future and hope are all...
誰かが描く遠い庭の
...in a distant garden drawn by someone,
わがままな物語
...a selfish story.
まだ誰も知らない
...that no one knows yet.
ひたむきな小鳥の声で歌う
Singing with the voice of a single-minded bird,
子供は何を隠し、何を壊し
what does the child hide, and what do they destroy?
燃える時計 秘めつめく花の香り
A burning clock, the scent of flowers whispering secrets.
ここにいるよ
I am here.
静かに寄り添って
Snuggling up quietly,
どこにも行かないで
please don't go anywhere.
窓辺でさえずって
Chirp by the window,
何を失くしたって
no matter what you lose.
夢はその腕の中に
Dreams are in those arms,
優しい人の嘘も嘆きも
locking away both the kindness...
閉じ込めていた
...and the grief of people.
何か足りない心で
With a heart that lacks something,
光を纏い込んで
clothed in light,
行こう 少女の形をして
let's go, in the form of a young girl.
終わらない始まりへ
To the beginning that never ends.
本当の終わりへ
To the true end.
静かに寄り添って
Snuggling up quietly,
どこにも行かないで
please don't go anywhere.
窓辺でさえずって
Chirp by the window,
どこにも行かないで
please don't go anywhere.
本日は、アキロゼ4周年ライブ「ROSE of the LAMP」いかがでしたかー！
How was Akirose's 4th Anniversary LIVE "ROSE of the LAMP" today?!
はい！それでは、かっこいいオープニングから始まり、
Yes! Well, starting with the cool opening,
たくさんたくさん、歌わせていただきました。
I sang many, many songs.
5年目も活動頑張っていきたいと思いますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll keep doing my best in my 5th year too, so please keep supporting me!
さあ、ここで超ハッピーなお知らせ、ドーーーン！
Now, here's some super happy news, boom!
4周年を記念して、スペシャルなグッズを作らせていただきました！
To celebrate the 4th anniversary, I've made some special goods!
今回のライブ＆新曲「ROSE of the LAMP」のロゴを
They're an acrylic keychain and stickers featuring the logo...
モチーフにした、アクキーとステッカー。
...of this LIVE and my new song "ROSE of the LAMP."
＆新曲ビジュアルのブランケットは、
And the blanket with the new song's visual...
千広彩香先生描き下ろしです！ぜひ、ゲットしてね！
...was drawn by Chihiro Ayaka-sensei! Please get them!
あれ？これは噂のアキロゼ睡眠事件？
Oh? Is this the rumored Akirose sleeping incident?
この黒Tシャツを着て、
Wearing this black T-shirt,
この後はメンバーシップ限定のアルコール・アンコールライブに、
after this, for the membership-only Alcohol Encore LIVE,
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
バイバーーイ！
Bye-byeee!
5年目も応援よろしくね！
Support me in my 5th year too!
新曲＆グッズGET報告まってます♡
Waiting for your reports on getting the new song & goods!